Guide to the Faculty of Arts and Science Department of Music Student Composition Recordings and Concert Ephemera MC 250
New York University Archives
Faculty of Arts and Science Department of Music Student Composition Recordings and Concert Ephemera
1990-2011
MC 250
New York University Archives
3.0 boxes Collection comprises 146 recordings on DAT, audio cassette, miniDV cassette, and CD as well as a small folder of papers (concert programs, notes, posters).
The Faculty of Arts and Science Department of Music Student Composition Recordings and Concert Ephemera consists of 147 audiovisual recordings of new music compositions by students of the FAS Music Department. Audio recordings of performances, rehearsals, and studio sessions constitute the vast majority of the collection’s materials, though it also contains four video recordings of interviews with visiting composer Elliott Carter. One folder of print and manuscript ephemera accompanies the audio recordings.
New York University. Faculty of Arts and Science. Music Department.
Provenance
The materials in the collection were transferred to the University Archives from the office of Louis Karchin, Professor of Music within the Faculty of Arts and Science (FAS).
History of Composition at the FAS Department of Music
The Music Department of the Faculty of Arts and Science was established in 1923. Upon the dissolution of the University Heights campus in 1972, the Washington Square College and University College programs were merged into one department at Washington Square. The M.A. track in Composition was added to the Department in 1989, with the first degree awarded in 1991. The following year saw the establishment of the Ph.D. program in Composition and Theory. As part of the composition track, the Department of Music sponsors concerts to showcase student composers' works. Outside groups, including the International Contemporary Ensemble, the League of Composers/ISCM, and the American Brass Quintet, have been hired to perform at many of these events, while some are sponsored directly by First Performance, an NYU graduate student composers' collective.
Access Restrictions
Open for use without restrictions.
This collection contains audiovisual materials that have not been digitized. Please contact the University Archives if you wish to access these materials.
Arrangement
The majority of the materials in the collection relate to performances of student composers’ finished works, though interviews with visiting composer Elliott Carter are also represented.
This collection is arranged chronologically in two series:
Recordings and Performances
Interviews
Scope and Contents
The Faculty of Arts and Science Department of Music Student Composition Recordings and Concert Ephemera consists of 147 audiovisual recordings of new music compositions by graduate and undergraduate students of the Music Department of the Faculty of Arts and Science (FAS). Audio recordings of performances, rehearsals, and studio sessions constitute the vast majority of the collection’s materials, though it also contains four video recordings of interviews with visiting composer Elliott Carter. One folder of print and manuscript ephemera accompanies the audio recordings in the form of annotated and unannotated performance programs and notes, posters, and concert announcements. An inventory spreadsheet of the recordings is also included.
Carter, Elliott, 1908-2012; New York University. Faculty of Arts and Science.; Audiocassettes.; DVDs; Interviews.; Musical performance.; New music; Posters.; Programs (documents).; Sound recordings.
- Series I: Recordings and Performances, 1990-2012
  - Programs and program notes, 1990-2012 (Box 6)
  - NYU GSAS Music Department April 3, 1990 dress rehearsal, 1990 April 3; 1.0 sound cassettes Business card of Susan Winthrop, Winthrop Productions found in case with cassette. (Box 1)
  - Composers Concert 3/26/91 I Zajonc, Royers, Goldkind, Smith, 1991 March 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - NYU Composers Concert 3/26/91 II Agustinovitch, Mercurio, Choi, 1991 March 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - NYU Composers Concert 3/26/91 Agustinovitch, Mercurio, Choi, 1991 March 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers Concert 2/2 - Agustinovitch, Mercurio, Choi, 1991 March 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers Concert 1/2 - Zajonc, Rogers, Goldkind, Smith, 1991 March 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers rehearsal - Goldkind, Smith, Rogers, 1991 March 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Michael Zajonc rehearsal 3/26/91, 1991 March 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - Moon Young Ha - somewhere fictitious for twelve instruments, 2011; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Felipe Lara - Quatre visoes contemporaneas na musica paulista, 2008; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - David McMullin composer, 2005; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Grace Choi - Chansons Innocents II, Ensemble Accroche Note, 2002; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Sean H. Carson - Red Harvest, 2002; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Sean H. Carson - Red Harvest and other music, 2002; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Christopher Ariza, 2002; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Jesse Sklar - Chamber Music, 2001; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - David Gordon - Green featuring the Talujon Quartet, the New York Virtuoso Singers, Curtis Macomber, Chris Fincker, Stephen Gosling, Holly Baughman, and Jesse Reagen, 2001; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - NYU Composers Concert 1992 back-up, 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Student Composers Concert afternoon rehearsal tape 1/2, 1992 March 31; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Student Composers Concert afternoon rehearsal tape 1/2, 1992 March 31; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Student Composers Concert performance, 1992 March 31; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Undergraduate Composers Concert back-up, 1992 April 21; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Undergraduate Composers 4/21/92 - Hauer, Harbison, Zybszynski, Webb, 1992 April 21; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - Concert 3/23/93 1-5, 1993 March 23; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers' Concert Apr. '93 Smith, Agustinovitch, Lionnet, Paul Baserman, Carmela Sinco, Emily Gitkin, 1993 April 1; 1.0 sound cassettes; Case label: #26; Insert label: Side A: Barry Smith Dark Matter (cl., pno., vcl., vln.), Vince Agustinovich Gift Horse (piano), Leonard Lionnet Finale from String Quartet (standard), Side B: Paul Baserman Summer Songs (May Swenson, text) (cl., basset hrn., bass cl., soprano), Carmela Sinco String Quartet #1 (3 mvts.), Emily Gitkin - Trio #2 (pno., vcl., fl.) (Box 1)
  - NYU 4/13/94 rehearsal tape 1/3, 1994 April 13; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU 4/13/94 tape 2/3 copy, 1994 April 13; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Concert 4/13/94 tape #1/3 copy, 1994 April 13; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU 4/13/94 Concert tape 3/3 copy, 1994 April 13; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU 4/13/94 Concert tape 3/3, 1994 April 13; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU 4/13/94 tape 2/3, 1994 April 13; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers rehearsal 5/2/95 copy, 1995 May 2; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers rehearsal 5/2/95 tape 1/1, 1995 May 2; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) Duration 1:37:15. (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers 5/2/95 (performance), 1995 May 2; 1.0 sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - NYU Composers 5/2/95 (performance), 1995 May 2; 1.0 sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - NYU Composers performance 5/2/95 tape #1/1, 1995 May 2; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) Duration 1:00:15. (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers performance 5/2/95 - performance (copy), 1995 May 2; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers 4-23-96 Concert, 1996 April 23; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers dress rehearsal tape 1/3 May 6, 1996, 1996 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers dress rehearsal tape 3/3 May 6, 1996, 1996 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers dress rehearsal tape 2/3 May 6, 1996, 1996 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers Concert 5/6/96, 1996 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - David McMullin: Quartet, 1996 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - NYU Composers Concert 5/6/1996 backup copy, 1996 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers Concert 5/6/96 tape 1/1, 1996 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - First Performance 12/8/96, 1996 December 8; 1.0 sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - First Performance 3/11/97 - McMullin, Conti, Richardson, Kingswood, 1997 March 11; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - First Performance 4/15/97 - Denton, Evans, McMullin, Genova, Conti, Conti, Kingswood, 1997 April 15; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers dress rehearsals 5/6/97, 1997 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 2)
  - NYU Composers May 6, 1997 afternoon run-through tape 1/1, 1997 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) Duration 1:54:01. (Box 4)
  - NYU Composers 5/6/97, 1997 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - NYU Composers 5/6/97 8 PM concert, 1997 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) Duration 1:35:34. (Box 4)
  - 98/02/06 First Performance master, 1998 February 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - First Performance 3/1/98 string quartet dress rehearsal, 1998 March 1; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - NYU - quartet concert 03-01-98 - Adamczyk, McMullin, Chang, Gordon, Kingswood, 1998 March 1; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - 98-04-28 NYU Composers Concert - McMullin, Evans, Adamczyk, Chang, Gordon, Richardson, Kingswood, 1998 April 28; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - Dress rehearsal 04-28-98 NYU - Gordon, Chang, Adamczyk, Kingswood, 1998 April 28; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) Duration ~107 minutes (Box 4)
  - 98-04-28 dress II NYU - Evans, McMullin, Richardson, 1998 April 28; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - First Performance - Adamczyk, Chang, Gordon, Kingswood, McMullin, Richardson, Trivers, 1998 December 6; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - First Performance 4/18/99 - Ha, Sklar, Chang, Adamczyk, Brett, Conti, Carson, 1999 April 18; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - First Performance 4/18/99, 1999 April 18; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - 99-04-26 dress 1, 1999 April 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - 99-04-26 NYU Composition Recital, 1999 April 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - 99-04-26 dress 2, 1999 April 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - NYU Composers Concert master April 26, 1999 part II, 1999 April 26; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - 99-05-02 First Performance String Quartet Concert - McMullin, Evans, Richardson, 1999 May 2; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - First Performance May 02, 1999 master copy, 1999 May 2; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - First Performance May 02, 1999 master copy, 1999 May 2; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - New Works by NYU Composers 12-02-99 - Conti, Kingswood, Richardson, Gordon, 1999 December 2; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - First Performance 12/8/99 - Carson, Gordon, Dorin, Richardson, 1999 December 8; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) Duration 41:21. (Box 4)
  - First Performance/Talujon 3/1/00 - Adamczyk, Dorin, Trivers, 2000 March 1; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - American Brass Quintet reading part I Richardson, Carson, 2000 April 18; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - American Brass Quintet reading part II Sklar, Kingswood, 2000 April 18; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - NYU Composers Concert 4/25/00 8 PM, 2000 April 25; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) Duration 1:23:45. (Box 4)
  - NYU Composers 4/25/00 rehearsal, 2000 April 25; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) Duration 2:03:00. (Box 4)
  - New York University Department Concert - Great Hall, Cooper Union, April 25, 2000, 2000 April 25; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - First Performance Choral Concert - N.Y. Virtuoso Singers, Harold Rosenbaum, 2000 May 2; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - First Performance - NY Virtuoso Singers, Director H. Rosenbaum 5/5/00 - Kingswood, Genova, Runowicz, McMullin, Carson, Richardson, 2000 May 5; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - Daniel Beliavsky, piano - Festival of the Hamptons, Guild Hall, 2000 July 20; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 4)
  - First Performance 11/29/2000 D&N, Kingswood, Carson, Gordon, Conti, Dorin, 2000 November 29; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - First Performance 4/18/01 + Talujon - Carson, Gordon, McMullin, Ariza, 2001 April 18; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - NYU Composers Concert May 1, 2001 afternoon recording, 2001 May 1; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - Cooper Union Student Composers 5/1/2001, 2001 May 1; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - May 7, 2001 First Performance, 2001 May 7; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - May 7, 2001 First Performance, 2001 May 7; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - Daniel Beliavsky - piano, Weigel Hall Auditorium, School of Music, Ohio State University, 2001 November 7; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - First Performance concert and dress - 11/16/2001 New York Virtuoso Singers, 2001 November 16; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - First Performance 4/4/02 Sklar, Gordon, Carson, 2002 April 4; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - First Performance 4/22/02 Dorin/Trivers/Somoroff/Kingswood, 2002 April 22; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Music by NYU Composers 5/8/02 Merkin Hall, 2002 May 8; 1.0 sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - 5-8-02 Dress A - Beliavsky, Trivers, Sklar, Schedler, 2002 May 8; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Department Composers Concert 5-8-02, 2002 May 8; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Music by NYU Composers 5-8-02 at 8PM Merkin Hall, 2002 May 8; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - 5-8-02 Dress B - Matthusen, Ariza, Carson, Jones, 2002 May 8; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - NYU Composers Concert 5/6/03 Merkin Hall, 2003 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Music by NYU Composers - Merkin Hall disc 1 of 2, 2003 May 6; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Music by NYU Composers - Merkin Hall disc 2 of 2, 2003 May 6; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Music by NYU Composers Merkin Hall 5/6/03 8PM, 2003 May 6; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - NYU First Performance Talujon, 2003 May 7; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - First Performance 12/4/03, 2003 December 4; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - David McMullin - Prague concert, 2004 December 3; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Dana Richardson - Spellbound, 2005 February 24; 1.0 sound discs (CD); Case label: #109; CD label: "Dana Richardson/Spellbound/All selections ASCAP/contact: richardson_dana@hotmail.com/[1]Spellbound- E. Bronte [2] Ode on Melacholy- Keats [3] I Look Into My Glass- Hardy [4] Ozymandias-Shelley/Anna Alexopoulou- soprano/Vicky Stylianou- piano, 2/24/05 Athens." (Box 3)
  - Music by NYU Graduate Composers CD 1 of 2 - Merkin Concert Hall, 2005 April 27; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Music by NYU Graduate Composers CD 2 of 2 - Merkin Concert Hall, 2005 April 27; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - NYU Graduate Composers - April 27, 2005 - Merkin Concert Hall, 2005 April 27; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - NYU Composers Concert - April 26, 2006 - Merkin Concert Hall - CD 1 of 2, 2006 April 26; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - NYU Composers Concert - April 26, 2006 - Merkin Concert Hall - CD 2 of 2, 2006 April 26; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Dana Richardson - 3rd House Concert 10/8/06, 2006 October 8; 1.0 sound discs (CD) Duration 32:28. (Box 3)
  - Dana Richardson - Ballade 3/12/07, 2007 March 12; 1.0 sound discs (CD) Duration 11:16. (Box 3)
  - Music by NYU Grad. Composers - The International Contemporary Ensemble - April 29, 2008, 2008 April 29; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Music by NYU Composers CD 1 of 1 - Merkin Concert Hall, 2008 April 29; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Wang Jie - A Longing For Spring - Continuum, 2011 May 1; 1.0 sound discs (CD) Duration 16:15. (Box 3)
  - Matthew Quayle - NYU Pieces 2002-04, 2002-2004; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Goldkind, Smith, Rogers rehearsal backup, undated; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Dress Rehearsal Composer Concert April 1993, 1993 April; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - First Performance 5/7, undated; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - NYU Composers Concert 3/26/91 Part I, 1991 March 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Performance Composers' Concert, undated; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - 126 - Rehearsal - John, Grace, Vince, undated; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Laura Evans: String Quartet #2, undated; 1.0 sound cassettes (Box 1)
  - Music by NYU Composers CD 1 of 2 - Merkin Concert Hall, 2007 April 30; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - The Animals Race by Daniel Beliavsky, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - NYU First Performance - Gordon, Carson, Dorin, Trivers copy 1, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - NYU First Performance - Gordon, Carson, Dorin, Trivers copy 2, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - NYU First Performance - Gordon, Carson, Dorin, Trivers copy 3, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - NYU First Performance - Gordon, Carson, Dorin, Trivers copy 4, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - NYU First Performance - Gordon, Carson, Dorin, Trivers copy 5, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - NYU First Performance - Gordon, Carson, Dorin, Trivers copy 6, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Alarm Will Sound rehearsal tape 1, undated; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Alarm Will Sound rehearsal 2, undated; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Alarm Will Sound performance tape 1, undated; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Alarm Will Sound tape 2 performance, undated; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 5)
  - Felipe Lara - Onda for orchestra - Berkshire Symphony Orchestra, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - McMullin - Ordinary Time, Crossings, Magnificat, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Felipe Lara - Corde Vocale, Onda, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Precipitation - Trivers, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Oppositions- Compositions by Juliana Trivers, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Apocrypha for solo piano composed and performed by Daniel Beliavsky, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Dana Dimitri Richardson - Chamber Music I, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
  - Compositions by Daniel Beliavsky, undated; 1.0 sound discs (CD) (Box 3)
- Series II: Interviews, 2002 February 26; 6.0 items (Box 4)
  - Elliott Carter interview and Q&A 26 Feb 2002, 2002 February 26; 1.0 videocassettes (MiniDV) (Box 4)
  - Elliott Carter 26 Feb 2002 interview, 2002 February 26; 1.0 videocassettes (MiniDV) (Box 4)
  - Elliott Carter interview at NYU 26 Feb 2002, 2002 February 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)
  - Elliott Carter 26 Feb 2002 Q&A, 2002 February 26; 1.0 videocassettes (MiniDV) (Box 4)
  - Elliott Carter interview and Q&A 26 Feb 2002, 2002 February 26; 1.0 videocassettes (MiniDV) (Box 4)
  - Elliott Carter at NYU 2/26/02 Q&A, 2002 February 26; 1.0 sound cassettes (DAT) (Box 4)